PRATAP ADHIKARI

Darwin, NT 0800 ◆ 0431305009 ◆ pratapadhikari37@gmail.com
https://pratapadhikari.netlify.app
PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY
I am a passionate and determined professional equipped with diverse skill-set and considerable experience in an assortment of web technologies. Being worked in different professions has helped me to adopt to the changes quickly and made me a mature team worker. I am committed to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills.
EDUCATION —
Master: Softwer Engineering, 2016
Charles Darwin University - Darwin
Bachelor: Computer Application, 2005 Pokhara University - Nepal
Work History

Room Attendant /Supervisor, 07/2015 to 04/2020

Jani King Pty Ltd, Australia – Darwin, NT

- Supervise/Manage team of over 15 staffs.
- Assign workers their duties and inspect work to ensure prescribed standards are maintained.
- Investigate complaints regarding housekeeping services and take corrective action.
- Worked with front desk to respond promptly to all guest requests.
- Trained and mentored all new personnel to maximise quality of service and performance.
- Communicated repair needs to maintenance staff.
- Completed schedules, shift reports and other business documentation.
- Adhered to safety protocols by enforcing proper equipment usage.

Front End Developer, 03/2012 to 06/2014

Sunbi Design Studio – Kathmandu, Nepal

- Developed responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant websites.
- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm enhanced web products.
- Developed reusable code that could minimize the time needed to complete projects in the future.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Delivered user support to clients to train, educate and answer questions.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.

Computer Science Teacher, 07/2006 to 01/2012

Shaheed Smriti Multiple Campus – Ratnanagar, Chitwan

- Delivered engaging curriculum through diverse methods, including classroom instruction, computer lab activities and online learning systems.
- Taught wide range of courses including C, JavaScript, XML, XSL/XSLT, HTML, CSS, SQL, Microsoft Access, Microsoft Office, simple networking, and basic hardware and software installation and maintenance.
- Delivered clear, effective feedback to improve quality and efficiency of student-written computer programs.
- Monitored, assessed, and documented student progress.
- Conducted training for staff and teachers about the basics of computer/Internet.

SKILLS

- Understanding of software development lifecycle best practices
- Ability to write high-performance, reusable code for UI components
- Detail-oriented work ethic with strong commitment to code quality
- Understanding of responsive design and progressive enhancement development best practices

- Good understanding of algorithms and data structures
- Analytical thinking skills
- Coding and Scripting
- Debugging & Troubleshooting

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- JavaScript/ HTML5/CSS3
- XML, XSL/XSLT, XPATH
- React Js/Next Js
- Material UI/Styled Components/SCSS
- React Native
- Node Js/Express Js
- SQL
- Firebase
- GIT